

ABHISHEK YADAV

GET IN CONTACT

Mobile: +91-7041433784

148-A, LN City, Gandhi Nagar, Indore, M.P.-453112 abhisheky579@gmail.com LinkedIn: @abhishek-yadav-170217a6

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Fashion Management Student with 6 years of experience in Garment Industry as Merchandiser with keen interest in the field of Category management and Buying/Sourcing. I am eager to add my knowledge and experience in a managerial role in the future.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- · Woven and Knits Garments
- Accessories and Trims Detailing
- · TNA Management
- Costing
- Vendor Management
- · Sales and stock Management
- Social media Management

SOFTWARE SKILL

- MS Office
- SAP
- SPSS
- R

OTHER SKILLS

- · Strong people skills
- Ability to work under pressure
- · Good interpersonal skills
- · Believe in Team work
- Positive approach towards work and the subordinates
- Goal oriented and a go getter attitude towards work

EDUCATION HISTORY

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF FASHION TECHNOLOGY, GANDHINAGAR

Mater in Fashion Management,

- · Specialization in Marketing and Retailing
- Elective subject Fashion Communication

SHRI VAISHNAV INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY AND SCIENCE

Bachelor of Engineering, 2014

- Specialization in Textile Technology
- Collage Discipline Committee member and Volunteer in the Organizing Committee of TAI (Textile Association of India).
- · School and college level Kho-Kho Winner.

INTERNSHIP

DA MILANO (2021)

· Department: Merchandising

ARVIND LTD. (2013)

· Department: Spinning

WORK EXPERIENCE

MERCHANDISER MANAGER/PLANNER

Arvind Limited | 2018 - 2020

- Production follow-up from different job centers.
- JC (Vendor) management.
- Planning for production with different Job Center.
- Planning with processing house for on-time in-housing of fabric.
- Follow up with the purchase & production team for on-time in-housing the material.
- Stock management- Monthly reconciliation of close order.

SENIOR MERCHANDISER

Banswara Garments | 2016 - 2018

- Discussion with the production team at the beginning of the season and plan according to the projection quantity given by the buyer.
- Planning of tentative dispatch schedule according to the capacity of factory and make tentative TNA.
- After getting the final details from the buyer, planning of production and dispatching it.
- Making final TNA as per the delivery date and execution according to the TNA.
- Offer open cost to the buyer and doing costing closer with them.
- Submitting all types of samples (PROTO/FPT/PP/GPT/TOP samples) on time, all Trim in-housing, and communicate with buyer for approval and other queries.
- Look-up of production during the time of order. Running, checking the daily status, and update the DPR and Buyer as well.
- Planning for Inspection & arranging QA.

WORK EXPERIENCE ACHIEVEMENT

- Our Team won best vendor performer in 2017 (from Pantaloons)
- 100% on time Shipment in continues 2 season 2018 (for Color Plus Brand)

HOBBY

- Cooking
- Reading

MERCHANDISER

Komal Tex Fab Pvt. Ltd. 2014-2016

- Communicating with buyers by mail (mostly) for new queries as well as updates.
- Submission of samples to the buyer.
- Follow up with buyers for approvals and feedback.
- Approving samples where buyer intervention is not required.
- Update the buyers with the order status at all stages.
- Execution of running orders (production).
- · Updating Time and Action calendar.
- Planning for new season sampling and production orders.
- Sourcing of materials for new development.